

Chaitanya Chavda

Business Development Executive

My Contact

- Chaitanya.chavda91@gmail.com
- +91 9067038027
 - Ahmedabad, Gujarat
 - www.linkedin.com/in/chaitanyachavda/

Hard Skill

- Email Marketing expert(Sendinblue, etc)
- CRM tools(Zoho, Salesforce, etc.)
- · Cold Calling
- Only international clientele(USA & UK)
- Business valuation/ SaaS
- Online Bidding(Upwork, etc)
- LI: Sales Navigator
- Online Campaigns
- Digital Marketing

Soft Skill

- Communication Excellence
- Technical Knowledge
- Research Skills
- Multi-tasking
- Good Observer
- · Negotiation Skills
- Passionate
- Self motivated
- Out-of-the-box thinking

Education Background

Ahmedabad University

Masters of Computer Applications

Completed in 2015

Bachelors of Computer Applications

Completed in 2013

About Me

I am an expert in business growth with a solid sales and business development background. The persuasive negotiator who presents joint ventures evaluates acquisition opportunities and pinpoints new markets with professionalism and integrity. Innovative thinker who identifies more effective ways to expand the company's assets through recommending new products, revolutionizing existing product offers, and testing novel marketing strategies.

Professional Experience

CygnetInfotech | Business Development Executive June 2022 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Increase Sales Volume by Expanding the product line to new clients, using different sources to pitch the client
- · Lead generation and maintain the CRM
- Maintained long-term relationships with clients and found new ones by identifying needs and offering appropriate services
- Product/service demo call to new clients
- Delivered engaging sales presentations to clients
- Prepare reports on the above information and communicate the insights of these reports to the broader business
- Consult with the management team to develop long-term commercial plans
- Suggest budgets and improvements based on the above information
- Email marketing using Sendinblue, MailMerge, etc.
- Cold/warm callings
- Online bidding on Upwork, etc.
- LinkedIn: Sales Navigator
- B2B Sales pitch SaaS
- · Proposal writing
- Email writing
- Documentation like NDA, SOW
- Prepare presentation using PowerPoint/ Prezi/ Canva
- Build Sales Pipeline
- · International timing shift
- Lead generation by Expanding the product line to new clients, using different sources to pitch the client
- Maintain relationships with clients & client communication
- Online bidding on Upwork, Fiverr, Guru, etc.
- Online campaigns
- Handel social media platforms like Quora, LinkedIn, Twitter, Dribble, Reddit, Facebook, Instagram, etc.
- Proposal writing

Professional Experience

SixBerries Ltd | Business Development Executive May 2021 - June 2022

- We partner with non-technical founders and SMEs to grow ideas into products and businesses
- Providing Ecommerce web development Solutions WordPress, Magento, Shopify technologies

Professional Experience

TatvaSoft| Business Development Executive April 2018 - April 2021

- Research and identify new business opportunities including new markets, growth areas, trends, customers, partnerships, products and services - or new ways of reaching existing markets
- Seek out the appropriate contact in an organization.
- Foster and develop relationships with customers/clients.
- Develop the business sales and marketing strategy.

Professional Experience

Zealousweb Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Business Development Executive Jan 2016 - March 2018

- Generating demands among customer for marketing services in the
- international market.
- Demand Generation (Leads, Opportunities Management)
- Customer Intelligence (Profiling and management of clients/target client's strategic information)
- Coordinate Business Development Activities.
- Analyse and generate new BDS
- Prepare and Communicate Information to Senior Management.
- Create an environment oriented to trust, open communication, creative thinking, and cohesive team effort.
- Maintain healthy group dynamics
- Encourage creativity, risk-taking, and constant improvement
- Lead nurturing, follow up with prospects till closure.
- Mapping global markets, capturing market intelligence and defining the target market for client's product or services.